A Finding Aid to the Holger Cahill Papers, 1910-1993, bulk 1910-1960, in the Archives of American Art
Archives of American Art
Holger Cahill papers
1910-1993
bulk 1910-1960
Archives of American Art
Cahill, Holger, 1887-1960
AAA.cahiholg
Archival Resource Key
15.8 Linear feet
The papers of Holger Cahill (1887-1960) date from 1910 to 1993, with the bulk of the material dating from 1910-1960, and measure 15.8 linear feet. The collection offers researchers fairly comprehensive documentation of Cahill's directorship of the Works Progress/Projects Administration's (WPA) Federal Art Project (FAP) in addition to series documenting his work as a writer and art critic. Material includes correspondence, reports, artist files, scrapbooks, printed material, and photographs.
Biographical Note
Holger Cahill was born Sveinn Kristjan Bjarnarson in Iceland in a small valley near the Arctic Circle, on January 13, 1887. His parents, Bjorn Jonson and Vigdis Bjarnadottir, immigrated to the United States from Iceland sometime later in the 1880s. In 1904, his father deserted the family, forcing Sveinn to be separated from his mother and sister to work on a farm in North Dakota. He ran away and wandered from job to job until settling in an orphanage in western Canada, where he attended school and became a voracious reader.
As a young man, he worked at many different jobs and attended night school. While working on a freighter, he visited Hong Kong, beginning his life-long interest in the Orient. Returning to New York City, he eventually became a newspaper reporter, continued his studies at New York University, and changed his name to Edgar Holger Cahill. In 1919 he married Katherine Gridley of Detroit. Their daughter, Jane Ann, was born in 1922, but the couple divorced in 1927.
Cahill met John Sloan circa 1920, and they shared a residence. Cahill also wrote publicity (until 1928) for the Society of Independent Artists, through which he made many friends in the arts. From 1922 to 1931, he worked under John Cotton Dana at the Newark Museum, where he received his basic experience in museum work, organizing the first large exhibitions of folk art.
From 1932 to 1935, he was the director of exhibitions for the Museum of Modern Art. In 1935, Cahill was appointed director of the Works Progress/Projects Administration (WPA) Federal Art Project (FAP), until its end in June 1943. In 1938, Cahill organized a countrywide exhibition "American Art Today" for the New York World's Fair. He also married MoMa curator Dorothy Canning Miller in that year.
Profane Earth, Cahill's first novel, was published in 1927, followed by monographs on Pop Hart and Max Weber, miscellaneous short stories, and a biography of Frederick Townsend Ward, entitled A Yankee Adventurer: The Story of Ward and the Taiping Rebellion. Following the end of the Federal Art Project, Cahill wrote two novels, Look South to the Polar Star (1947) and The Shadow of My Hand (1956).
Holger Cahill died in Stockbridge, Massachusetts in July 1960.
Scope and Content Note
The papers of Holger Cahill (1887-1960) date from 1910 to 1993, bulk 1910-1960, and measure 15.8 linear feet. The collection offers researchers fairly comprehensive documentation of Cahill's directorship of the FAP in addition to series documenting his work as a writer and art critic. FAP records include national and state administrative reports, records of community art centers, photographic documentation of state activities, artist files, divisional records about teaching, crafts, murals, and poster work, files concerning the Index of American Design, scrapbooks, and printed material.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged into nine series:
Missing Title
Series 1: Biographical Material and Personal Papers, 1931-1988 (Box 1; 19 folders)
Series 2: Correspondence Files, 1922-1979, 1993 (Boxes 1-2; 1.5 linear ft.)
Series 3: Works Progress Administration Federal Art Project, 1934-1970 (Boxes 2-14, 18, MMs009; 10.75 linear ft.)
Series 4: Writings, Lectures and Speeches, 1916-1960 (Boxes 14-15, 18; 1.0 linear ft.)
Series 5: Minutes of Meetings and Panel Discussions, Non-FAP, 1939-1947 (Box 15; 5 folders)
Series 6: Notes and Research Material, 1935-1970 (Boxes 15-16; 0.25 linear ft.)
Series 7: Artwork, undated (Boxes 16, 18; 2 folders)
Series 8: Printed Material, 1910-1985 (Boxes 16-17; 1.8 linear ft.)
Series 9: Photographs, circa 1917-1960 (Box 17; 6 folders)
Provenance
The Holger Cahill papers were donated to the Archives of American Art through a series of gifts by Cahill's widow, Dorothy C. Miller, between 1964 and 1995.
Restrictions on Access
The microfilm of this collection has been digitized and is available online via the Archives of American Art website.
Alternative Forms Available
The papers of Holger Cahill in the Archives of American Art were digitized in 2004 from 20 reels of microfilm, and total 30102 images.
Prints; Government records; Interviews; Scrapbooks; Photographs; Slides (photographs); Federal aid to the public welfare; Art and state; Federal aid to the arts; New Deal, 1933-1939; United States -- Economic conditions -- 1918-1945; United States -- Social conditions -- 1933-1945; Arts administrators; Public officers; Photograph albums; Drawings; American Federation of Arts; Artists' Union (New York, N.Y.); Brown, Samuel Joseph, 1907-1994; Cartoonists Guild; De Rivera, José Ruiz, 1904-1985; Federal Art Project (U.S.); Federal Theatre Project (U.S.); Federal Music Project (U.S.); Hopkins, Harry Lloyd, 1890-1946; Halpert, Edith Gregor, 1900-1970; Abbott, Berenice, 1898-1991; Index of American Design; American Council of Learned Societies; New York World's Fair (1939-1940: New York, N.Y.); Rowan, Edward Beatty, 1898-1946; Scaravaglione, Concetta, 1900-1975; Speck, Walter, 1895-; Shakers; Ward, Lynd, 1905-1985; Weisenborn, Rudolph, b. 1881; American Artists' Congress; United States. Work Projects Administration; The Design Laboratory (New York, N.Y.); Treasury Relief Art Project; Morris, Carl, 1911-1993; United States. Works Progress Administration; Segal, George, 1924-2000; Olds, Elizabeth, 1896-1991; Roosevelt, Eleanor, 1884-1962; Knaths, Karl, 1891-1971; Miller, Dorothy Canning, 1904-2003
- Biographical Material and Personal Papers, 1931-1988; Series 1; Archival Resource Key; 19 Folders Box 1
  Scope and Contents note
  Biographical material includes nine typed career summaries/resumes for Cahill, dated circa 1935-1941. The resumes provide basically the same information with only minor variations in wording, with some handwritten notations and typed inserts to update the descriptions of Cahill's career through the early 1940s.
  Also found here is a transcript of an interview, "Reminiscences of Holger Cahill," conducted by Joan Pring; a 1961 letter from Cahill's sister; a document entitled "Notes on the life of Holger Cahill" by Cahill's wife, Dorothy C. Miller, which provide details of Cahill's childhood and his work; and a 1988 letter from Dorothy Miller enclosing a copy of Cahill's birth certificate dated 1887. The series also includes a copy of Time from September 5, 1938, picturing Cahill on the cover and an article about his work with the WPA.
  The series also includes financial records consisting primarily of receipts and balance sheets for artwork purchased and sold, many of them issued by the American Folk Art Gallery in which Cahill held a partnership with Edith Halpert and Berthe Kroll Goldsmith.
  - Biographical Material, circa 1935-1939; Archival Resource Key (Reel 1105, Frame 0012-0021)
  - Biographical Material, circa 1940-1988; Archival Resource Key (Reel 5285, Frame 0003-0026)
  - Financial Records, 1931-1938; Archival Resource Key (Reel 5287, Frame 1016-1035)
  - Financial Records, 1939-1940; Archival Resource Key (Reel 5287, Frame 1036-1062)
  - Financial Records, 1941-1950; Archival Resource Key (Reel 5287, Frame 1063-1096)
  - Financial Records, 1942-1956; Archival Resource Key (Reel 5287, Frame 1097-1119)
  - Interview Transcript, 1957; Archival Resource Key (Reel 5285, Frame 0027-0653)
  - Interview Transcript, Index, 1957; Archival Resource Key (Reel 5285, Frame 0654-0670)
- Correspondence Files, 1922-1979, 1993; Series 2; Archival Resource Key; 1.5 Linear feet Boxes 1-2
  This series consists of personal and work-related correspondence (primarily incoming correspondence) between Cahill and various friends and colleagues. While a large portion of the series documents Cahill's position as Director of the FAP, it also extends beyond those years and illuminates other aspects of Cahill's career including his interest in folk and Asian art, and his work as an art critic.
  There is significant correspondence with the artist Stanton MacDonald Wright between 1936 and 1950, and with the artist Irene Pereira between 1950 and 1953. The series also documents research which Cahill conducted in the late 1940s on the development of the Index of American Design for his introduction to a book on the Index by the National Gallery of Art, published by the Macmillan Company. Correspondence from 1949 provides another angle on the historical details of the FAP through lengthy correspondence documenting Cahill's criticism of William Francis McDonald's book Federal Relief Administration and the Arts (Ohio State University Press, 1969).
  There is a large amount of correspondence from July 1960 comprising sympathy letters to Dorothy C. Miller following Cahill's death. Correspondence from 1977 encloses a catalog of an exhibition organized by New York WPA Artists, Inc., at the Parsons School of Design in November 1977. The exhibition, New York City WPA Art, was dedicated to the memory of Holger Cahill.
  See Appendix for a list of correspondents (with the exception of those microfilmed on reel 1105) in Series 2.
  Appendix: Correspondents in Series 2
  Abbott, Berenice: 1944 (letter to the Editor)
  Abbott, John: [1946]
  Abell, Walter ( Canadian Art): 1943-1944 (2 letters)
  Adams, Charles C.: 1940
  Alcopley, Mr.: [1952] (including typescript "Pictures of Alcopley" by Saburo Hasegawa); 1953-1960 (4 letters)
  Alsberg, Henry G. (Director, Federal Writers' Projects): 1936 (4 letters)
  American Council of Learned Societies: 1949
  American Federation of Arts: 1949-1952 (3 letters)
  American Folk Art Gallery: 1941
  American Heritage: 1954
  American Swedish Historical Foundation: 1949
  Andrews, Robert Armstrong and Eleanor: [1960], undated
  Art in America: 1953
  Artists For Victory: [1942]
  Artists League of America: 1945
  Artists Union of Massachusetts: 1936 (telegram to President Roosevelt)
  Arts Council of Japanese Americans for Democracy: 1944
  Ashton, Dore: [1960]
  Bach, Richard F. (Metropolitan Museum): 1924 and 1950
  Bailey, Herbert: 1972 (letter from Naomi Bliven)
  Baker, Donald: [1936]
  Baker, Jacob (WPA): 1935-1960, undated (10 letters)
  Barach, Frederica (Writers' War Board): 1944
  Barker, Virgil and Ida: 1945-1960 (4 letters)
  Barnard College: 1951 (2 letters)
  Barr, Alfred H., Jr. (Museum of Modern Art): 1935-1960 (16 letters)
  Barr, Tony: 1960
  Batten, Barton, Durstine & Osborn, Inc.: 1950
  Baur, John (Brooklyn Museum): 1946-1960 (6 letters)
  Baylinson, Ada: 1950
  Bear, Donald J. (Denver Art Museum): 1939
  Beckmann, Mrs. Max: 1960
  Bennington College: 1950
  Benson, Emanuel M. (FAP): 1936-1940 (7 letters)
  Berlandina, Jane: 1960
  Bessinger, Frederic (artist): 1933
  Biddle, George: 1936-1940
  Biesel, Fred and Frances: 1941-1955 (13 letters)
  Bird, Elzy: [1949]
  Bittermann, Eleanor: 1951
  Black, Mary: [1960]
  Bliven, Naomi: 1972 (letter to Herbert Bailey)
  Block, Edgar S.: 1950
  Block, Lou: 1949
  Bluemner, Oscar: 1934-1937 (3 letters)
  Blue Ribbon Books: 1935
  Blume, Peter: 1944 and 1950
  Blumenfeld, Willow (Cahill's granddaughter): [1960]
  Blumenschein, Ernest L.: 1936
  Blumenthal, Joseph: [1960]
  Bolotowsky, Ilya: 1960
  Borgenicht, Grace (art dealer): [1960]
  Boston Marine Museum: 1949
  Boston: Museum of Fine Arts: 1950
  Boulton, Margaret: 1936
  Bragozzi, Tony and Olive (curator of David Rockefeller's collection): 1960
  Breck, George and Ruth: [1960]
  Brennan, Francis: 1960
  Brook, Alex: 1959 (2 letters)
  Brook, Gina (wife of artist Alexander Brook): 1960
  Brooks, James and Charlotte: [1960]
  Brown, Clara D. (antiques dealer): [1935]
  Brown, Yaeger: 1943 (2 letters)
  Bruce, Edward: 1937
  Bucks County Historical Society: 1950
  Bufano, Beniamino: [1940-1942], undated (3 letters)
  Bulau, Alwin E.: 1952
  Burnham, Ralph Warren (antiques dealer): 1933
  Byron, Evelyn S.: 1942 (memo from Wilda Sawyer)
  Bywaters, Jerry: 1960
  Calder, Alexander: 1956 (photocopy) and 1960
  Calkins, K: 1936 (2 letters to Constance Rourke)
  Campbell, Robert B.: 1960
  Carolina Art Association: 1935-1950 (5 letters)
  Carroll, Bob: 1960
  Carroll, Eleanor: 1936
  Castelli, Leo: 1960
  Catlin, Tod: 1960
  Cavanna, Elise: 1960
  Chamberlain, Betty: 1960
  Chanin, Abraham and Maralt (Museum of Modern Art): [1960]
  Chapin, Lucy Stock: 1932-1933 (2 letters)
  Chapman, Suzanne: 1946-1949 (2 letters)
  Charm (Barbara Lee Johnson): 1929
  Chermayeff, Serge (Institute of Design): 1948
  Chichester, Jim Hinchman (college friend of Elizabeth Holt): 1960
  Church, Elizabeth D. (antiques dealer): 1935 (including 10 photographs of folk art)
  Citizens Committee for Support of WPA: 1937
  Claflin, Agnes: 1960
  Clark, Stephen C.: 1939
  Cleveland Institute of Art: 1950 (letter from Alfred Barr)
  Coffey, Katherine: 1960
  Coggeshall, Calvert and Suzanne: 1956-1960 (2 letters)
  Cole, Mrs. Charley Tidd (Friends of the FAP): 1940 (letter from Martha Davidson)
  Colie, Annetta (Elizabeth Holt's sister): 1960
  Colin, Georgia and Ralph: 1960
  Collier, Nina (Index of American Design): 1936 (6 letters)
  Collins, Lloyd and Lib: 1960
  Colman, Anne (FAP, Michigan): 1937 (2 letters)
  Colonial Williamsburg, Incorporated: 1935-1960 (13 letters)
  Colorado Springs Fine Arts Center: 1939-1960 (3 letters)
  Columbia Broadcasting System, Inc.: 1939 (contract for Cahill to broadcast "What's Art to Me" program)
  Columbia University: [1939]
  Conklin, Franklin (Newark Museum): 1944
  Connolly, Elizabeth (FAP, Southern California): 1940
  Cooper, Charlotte Gowing (FAP, Ohio): 1937-1937 (4 letters)
  Cooper, Samuel C.: 1941 (including certificate of dissolution for the American Folk Art Gallery); 1951 (3 letters)
  Corcoran Gallery of Art: 1950 (3 letters)
  Cornelius, Charles: 1936 (2 memoranda from others)
  Cosmopolitan Fire Insurance: 1931
  Coussirat, Elizabeth (Index of American Design): 1936 (6 letters)
  Crampton, Rollin: 1960
  Craven, Thomas: 1944 (2 letters)
  Crawford, Phyllis: 1945-1960 (4 letters)
  Crofut, Edward F. (WPA and Museum of Modern Art): 1936-1938 (3 letters)
  Cronin, Agnes S.: 1939-1944 (2 letters)
  Crosby, Hildegard (FAP, Illinois): 1937-1949 (8 letters)
  Culler, Julia Abbott: 1935
  Cummin, Hazel (Index of American Design): 1937 (5 letters)
  Curran, Mary (FAP, Pennsylvania): 1937 (2 letters)
  Daly, Matthew A. (WPA): 1936 (2 letters)
  Dana, John Cotton (Newark Museum): 1924-1925 (4 letters)
  Daugherty, D. H. (American Council of Learned Societies): 1949 (11 letters)
  Davidson, Jo: 1944 (letter to the Editor)
  Davidson, Martha (Friends of the FAP): 1939-1940 (3 letters)
  Davies, Terry: 1960 (2 letters)
  Davis, Charles (artist): mentioned in invitation dated [1938]
  Davis, D. and Phyllis: 1960
  Davis, George Earl: 1952
  Davis, Lew and Mathilde: 1960
  Davis, Stuart: 1936-1960 (5 letters)
  Dehner, Dorothy: [1960]
  Delson, Sidney: 1958-1959 (2 letters)
  de Nagy, Tibor: 1960
  Dentsch, Hilda: [1941-1960] (2 letters)
  DeVoto, Bernard: 1949 (4 letters)
  De Young Memorial Museum: 1939
  d'Harnoncourt, Rene: 1944-1960 (5 letters)
  Dickinson, Edwin: 1960
  Dienes, Sari (artist): 1960
  Don, Michael: 1939-1940 (2 letters)
  Donati, Enric: 1960
  Douglas, Eric: 1949
  Downtown Gallery: 1935
  Dows, Olin (Treasury Relief Art Project): 1935-1960 (5 letters)
  Dunbar, Anna: 1960
  Duntley, Seibert Q.: 1941
  du Pont, H. F.: 1950 (2 letters)
  Durieux, Caroline: 1943
  Durham, Mr.: 1936
  Dutt, Alska: 1956
  du Von, Jay: 1941
  East Liverpool, Ohio, Chamber of Commerce: 1939
  Eaton, Allen: 1938 and 1945
  Edwards, Paul (WPA, Washington, D.C.): 1941
  Eglington, Laurie (Index of American Design): 1936 (2 letters)
  Eilshemius, Louis M.: 1931-1939 (2 letters)
  Emery, Humphrey J. (American Handicraft Council): 1939
  Emil, Allan and Kate (art collectors): 1960
  Emmerich, Andre: 1960
  Engineer Replacement Center, Fort Belvoir: 1941 (2 letters)
  Essex Institute: 1950
  Evans, Ernestine: 1947 (2 letters)
  Evergood, Philip: 1944 (letter to the Editor)
  Fairweather, Sally: [1960]
  Feininger, Julia: 1960, undated
  Feitelson, Lorser and Helen: 1943-1960 (3 letters)
  Ferber, Herbert and Lisi: 1960 (2 letters)
  Ferren, John: 1949 (2 letters)
  Field, George H. (Federal Works Agency): 1943 (2 letters)
  Flanagan, Hallie: 1949 (3 letters)
  Fleming, Philip B.: [1943]
  Fogel, Barbara: 1960
  Follmer, Frank J.: 1942
  Force, Juliana: 1946
  '47 Magazine: 1946
  Frankenberg, Lloyd: 1937 and 1960
  French, Helen: [1960]
  Frick Art Reference Library: 1946
  Fried: Rose Fried Gallery: 1953
  Friends of the FAP: 1939 (13 letters)
  Fuller, Buckminster: 1942-1949 (including a brochure about the Dymaxion House)
  Fultz, Harry T.: 1942 (memo from Fred Biesel)
  Gaskin, William: 1940-1961 (12 letters)
  Gates, Marguerite (Public Library of Newark, N.J.): 1929-1935 (3 letters)
  Gavert, Olive Lyford (Alfred Barr's secretary): 1960
  General Services Administration: 1950
  Gershoy, Toni: [1960]
  Gibbs, Peggy (widow of artist Howard Gibbs): [1960]
  Giedion, Siegfried: mentioned in letter dated Oct 07, 1951
  Glarner, Fritz: 1949 and 1960
  Glassgold, Cook Adolph: 1936-1940 (43 letters)
  Goldberg, Albert L. (Illinois Music Project): 1940
  Goldberg, Mike: [1960]
  Goldwater, Louise and Robert: 1960
  Goodall, Donald B.: 1960
  Goodchild, Donald: 1939
  Goodrich, Lloyd (Whitney Museum of American Art): 1948-1960 (7 letters)
  Goodyear, A. Conger: 1935-1960 (5 letters)
  Gordon, Jack (Whitney Museum of American Art): [1960]
  Gorsline, Douglas W.: 1950 (2 letters)
  Gowing, Lawrence: 1960
  Graham, Ralph (FAP, Illinois): 1941-1942 (3 letters)
  Graves, Morris: 1946
  Green, Wilder: 1960
  Greenberg, Clement: 1960
  Greenwell, Darrell J. ( Ogden Standard Examiner): 1949
  Griffis, Toni (Mrs. Hughes Griffis): 1960
  Griffith, E. J. (FAP, Oregon): 1938 and 1960
  Grossman, Mrs. I. Donald: [1960]
  Guerrero, Jose and Roxane: [1960]
  Guggenheim, Olga: 1960
  Gwathmey, Robert: 1944 (letter to the Editor)
  Hale, Bob (Metropolitan Museum of Art): 1960
  Hall, Edward T. (Universal School of Handicrafts): 1939
  Halpert, Edith: 1930-1960, undated (20 letters)
  Hardin, Shirley: [1960]
  Hare, Michael M.: 1948
  Harper's Magazine: 1943-1944 (2 letters)
  Harrison, Preston: 1934
  Hart, "Pop": 1930-1932 (2 letters)
  Hartigan, Grace: 1960
  Hasegawa, Saburo: 1952 (letter to Franz Kline, including typescript "Pictures of Alcopley")
  Hatch, John Davis: 1960
  Hatcher, Harry and Doris: 1960 (3 letters)
  Haupers, Clement (FAP, Minnesota): 1937-1949 (5 letters)
  Haydon, Hal: 1955
  Henley, Helen B. (Wadsworth Atheneum): 1937 (2 letters)
  Herbert, David: 1960
  Hess, Thomas: 1960
  Hinckley, Robert H. (American Broadcasting Co.): 1960
  Hirsch, Joseph: 1960
  Hofmann, Hans and Maria: 1960 (2 letters)
  Holt, Elizabeth (art historian): 1960
  Holzhauer, Mildred: 1937-1940 (4 letters)
  Hope, Henry R. (Indiana Univ.): 1948-1949 (2 letters)
  Hopkins, Harry L.: 1936-1943 (13 letters)
  Horr, Axel (artist): mentioned in invitation dated [1938]
  House Beautiful: 1950
  Houston: Museum of Fine Arts of Houston: 1955
  Hunter, Howard O.: 1941
  Hunter, Virginia and Russell Vernon Hunter: 1951-1960, undated (4 letters)
  Huxley, Julia S.: 1942
  Illinois Art Project: 1941-1942 (6 letters)
  Index of American Design: 1936 (form letter)
  Interior: Department of the Interior: 1950 (3 letters)
  Inverarity, Robert Bruce (FAP State Dir., Washington): 1937-1950 (5 letters)
  Isaacs, Betty and Julius: 1960
  Jackson, Martha: [1960]
  Jerry, Sylvester (FAP, Michigan): 1939 (3 letters)
  Johns, Jasper: 1960
  Johnson, Anna: 1952
  Johnson, Buffie: 1960
  Johnson, Irene Edith: 1960
  Johnson, Philip C.: 1960
  Jones, Anne (Mrs. E. Powis Jones): 1960
  Kallen, Horace (publisher): 1960
  Karpel, Ray and Bernard (Museum of Modern Art): [1960]
  Kavanaugh, George R. (Berea College): 1936
  Kaye, Harold: 1958
  Kayser, Dr.: 1954
  Keck, Caroline and Sheldon (art conservators): 1960
  Kellogg, Elizabeth R.: 1949 (2 letters)
  Kent, Rockwell: 1944
  Kerr, Florence (Work Projects Administration): 1940-1942 (4 letters)
  Keyes, Homer Eaton ( Antiques Magazine): 1936
  Kiesler, Frederick J.: 1960
  Kiplinger, Walter M.: 1941 (4 letters)
  Kipper, Katrina (antiques dealer): 1935 (3 letters)
  Kirby, Mr. O. A.: 1941
  Kleinholz, Frank: 1944 (letter to the Editor)
  Kline, Franz: 1952 (letter from Saburo Hasegawa, including typescript "Pictures of Alcopley") and 1960
  Knight, Frederic (Artists' Coordination Committee): Nov 1936 (5 letters)
  Knight, Harry: 1960
  Knittle, Rhea Mansfield: 1936-1937 (2 letters)
  Kokoschka, Oskar: 1944
  Kootz, Jane and Sam: 1960
  Kroll, Eleanor: 1937 (2 letters)
  Kuniyoshi, Yasuo: 1944 (2 letters)
  Labaudt, Lucien: 1943 (4 letters)
  Lane, Harry: [1960]
  Laning, Clair: 1960
  Leech, Nancy T.: 1949
  Leeds, Harold Eliot (architect): 1960
  Legg, Alicia (Museum of Modern Art curator): 1960
  Leggett, Eugene S. (National Emergency Council): 1936 (letter from Harry Hopkins)
  Leicester, Louise B. (American Handicraft Council): [1940]
  Lekakis, Michael: 1960
  Lemmon, Warren W.: mentioned in letter dated Mar 08, 1940
  Levine, Jack: 1960
  Levy, Julian: 1944 and [1960]
  Lewis and Clark High School: 1939
  Lewis, Elizabeth Ray: 1943
  Life Magazine: 1944 (4 letters)
  Lipman, Jean and Howard: [1960]
  Lipscomb, Isabel (Work Projects Admin.): 1941 (3 letters)
  Lipton, Seymour: [1960]
  Litchfield, Elizabeth (Museum of Modern Art): 1941 - [1960] (3 letters)
  Lowenthal, Edith and Milton: 1960
  Lundy, Margaret: 1938
  Lunsford, Bascom Lamar: 1936
  Lyles, Mary E.: 1935
  Mabry, Tom and Ethel: 1960 (2 letters)
  Macdonald-Wright, Stanton: 1936-1955, undated (60 letters)
  Macdowell Colony: 1960
  MacLeish, Archibald: [1943] (letter from Philip B. Fleming)
  Macmillan Company: 1946-1959 (24 letters)
  Magazine of Art: 1948-1951 (10 letters)
  Mapes, Col. Milton C. (Civilian Camouflage): 1941
  March, Frank A. (Project Control Division): 1941
  Marcus, Marcia: 1960
  Marg Magazine: 1956 (6 letters)
  Marx, Ione F.: 1942
  Maryland Historical Society: 1950 (2 letters)
  Matisse, Patricia (Pierre Matisse Gallery Corp.): [1960]
  Mattis, Astria: 1960
  Maverick Maury (Congressman, Texas): 1936 (3 letters)
  Mayor, A. Hyatt (Metropolitan Museum): 1960
  Mazo, Sara (widow of Yasuo Kuniyoshi): 1960
  McAndrew, Betty and John: 1960
  McCormick, M. R.: 1938
  McCrady, John: 1943
  McCray, Porter (Museum of Modern Art): 1960
  McDonald, W. F. (American Council of Learned Societies): 1944-1949 (3 letters)
  McKeague, Robert I. (Community Service Projects Section): 1937-1940 (8 letters)
  McMahon, Audrey (WPA): 1936-1941 (7 letters)
  McPharlin, Paul (Michigan WPA): 1937 (7 letters)
  Metropolitan Museum of Art: 1953
  Miller, Dorothy C. (Museum of Modern Art): 1936-1956 (27 letters)
  Miller, Emma Guffey: 1938
  Minnesota Historical Society: 1952
  Morgan, Anne: 1938-1939 (5 letters)
  Morley, Grace: 1960
  Morris, Lawrence: 1937-1939 (2 letters)
  Morris, Suzy (Mrs. George L. K. Morris): 1960
  Morrison, Richard: 1936-1949 (6 letters)
  Morsell, Miss: 1938
  Motherwell, Robert: 1960
  Museum of Modern Art: 1936-[1960] (4 letters)
  Myers, Bernard: 1948
  Myers, John (art dealer): 1960
  Nakian, Reuben: 1960